Speaker: Fascinating facts about sugar and salt.
At different times in history, both sugar and salt were called ‘white gold’
because they were so expensive and difficult to get.
And there are many more interesting facts about sugar and salt…
Salt is used to make glass, washing powder, and paper.
People often think that sugar makes children more active or that it makes them behave badly.
However, there is no strong scientific evidence of this.
Salt was very valuable in ancient Rome.
Soldiers were paid extra money called ‘salarium’ especially to buy it,
and this is where the word ‘salary’ comes from.
Scientists use sugar to make different kinds of plastic, for example, for food packaging.
Only 6% of the salt used in the USA is used in food;
the remaining 94% is used for things like farming and de-icing roads.
Sure and sugar are the only two words in the English language
that begin with ‘s’ and are pronounced ‘sh’.
In the UK, there’s a club for people who collect the little packets of
sugar you get when you order tea or coffee in a café or restaurant.
Salt removes red wine stains (though probably not from your new white carpet).
If you put sugar into a vase of flowers, the flowers last longer.
The body of an average adult has about 250 g of salt.
It helps oxygen to travel around the body and makes muscles work.
Salzburg, the city in Austria where Mozart was born, means ‘castle of salt ’.
Christopher Columbus introduced sugar to the Americas in 1493 on his second voyage.